# **Kelly Tate**

Seattle, Washington | kelly.tate.dev@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

## **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Recent graduate of Ada Developers Academy full stack software engineering boot camp with a passion for continuous learning, problem-solving, and optimization. Transitioning to software development after 4+ years of study in computer science and development. Bringing leadership, communication, creativity, and versatility honed through 7+ years of teaching and over 9 years of collaborating in fast-paced, customer-focused retail and marketing environments.

## **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, Java, C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, PHP

• Frameworks & Libraries: Flask, Django, React/Native, Node.js, Next.js, Spring Boot, WordPress

Tools: Git, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Prisma

Testing: Pytest, JUnit, Jest

Cloud Technologies: Heroku, GCP, AWS, Vercel, OpenShift

• Development Environments: VSCode, Expo, IntelliJ, PyCharm, Eclipse, Xcode

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Beverage and Cheese Pairing App - Website

Al-powered recommendation app built with Svelte, OpenAl, and Vercel

- Built as a personal workplace tool to improve customer service regarding cheese and beverage pairings
- Leveraged Vercel Edge function templates and added features to auto-suggest relevant search options and links to search for recommended products on external websites

# Ada Developers Academy CMS - Website

CMS site for non-profit coding bootcamp built on WordPress with PHP and CSS

- Collaborated on migration to a new WordPress implementation to consolidate theme customization and improve site maintainability
- Incorporated Agile principles using a Kanban approach to task management, accountability, and communication, and pair-programming to ensure consistency for the 2-member developer team
- Improved SEO performance, streamlined the editing workflow, and created documentation for an administrative staff of 20+

#### Limn - Github

Django social media journal app integrating APIs including Spotify, LocationIQ, and Cloudinary

- Collaborated on a 2-person team throughout the development lifecycle, from determining requirements, wireframes, database design, and testing to implementation and debugging with Django, Pytest, and PostgreSQL and deployment with Heroku
- Enhanced multimedia journal entries with calls to 5+ external APIs for attachment of images, videos, single tracks and playlists, location mapping, calendars, and data visualizations

## **Inspiration Board – Github**

Message board app using API calls between React and the Flask and PostgreSQL back-end

- Developed in coordination with a 5-member development team, according to provided specifications using Kanban techniques for communication and Git version control and code reviews
- Connected Flask CRUD API functionality with React front-end allowing users to create, view, and like brief
  inspirational messages using React components; tested with Pytest and Jest

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

To The SHE Power Remote

Contract Full Stack Developer/Engineer

2023 - current

- Consulted on the brand design of a new web application product
- Implemented the integration of multiple cloud services for authentication, database access, and resource management as a member of a 3-person development team

SquareHook Remote

Contract Front-End Developer

2023 - 2023

- Contributed to the front-end implementation of a user dashboard for managing assets as part of a 3-person developer team
- Customized and leveraged a third-party graph library to visually represent user account data according to requirements of the design team

# **Ada Developers Academy**

Seattle, WA

Full Stack Engineer Intern

2023 - 2023

- Established requirements for a 4-month project to implement a clean-code rebuild of a CMS-powered website in partnership with marketing and leadership teams
- Developed layouts and reusable blocks according to marketing team specifications increasing workflow speed for non-technical staff by 30%

Whole Foods Market Chapel Hill, NC

**Grocery Team Trainer** 

2019 – 2022

- Named 2021 Regional All-Star Team Member of the Year for leadership and performance at a store of 200+
- Spearheaded workflow optimization for the grocery team's weekly performance report reducing execution time by 25%

# **Self-Employed Photographer**

Baton Rouge, LA; Kansas City, MO/KS

Real Estate Photographer

2013 - 2019

 Pioneered expansion market as an exclusive contract photographer for New Orleans-based small business, establishing loyal relationships with local agents, increasing the company's service markets by 20%

# **Louisiana State University School of Art**

Baton Rouge, LA

Instructor of Art

2009 - 2014

• Taught 5+ course topics ranging from basic to advanced applications of photography and basic design and digital art

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Ada Developers Academy**

2022 - 2023

Full Stack Web Development

Python, Flask, Django, JavaScript, React

**Computer Science Fundamentals** 

Data structures and algorithms

#### **Wake Tech Community College**

2019 - 2022

Certificates: Programming Fundamentals, C++ Programming, Java Programming

- Cloud application development: AWS, GCP, OpenShift, VMware
  - Agile Development: Scrum, Kanban

#### **Louisiana State University**

2008 - 2011

Master of Fine Arts – Photography

Bachelor of Arts - German Language & Literature